and today we are going to learn how to
build awesome beautiful presentations
for the web using a super cool
presentation framework called reveal.js
using reveal.js we can build interactive
web presentations that have a lot of
features using just HTML reveal.js
generates slides for us it supports
vertical slides it supports code syntax
code animations and highlighting Element
Animations it supports markdown and it
has slight fragments that can be
customized and animated it also supports
Custom Image videos and gifs backgrounds
for our slides it also has a background
and slide transitions among many other
things so let's get started here is how
our HTML looks like here we are
importing three CSS files and two
JavaScript files all of these files we
can download from the reveal.js GitHub
revealed that CSS are the base styles
for our slide black CSS is the theme
that we want our slides to have there
are other things we can choose as well
monokai CSS is what will make our code
look pretty on the JavaScript side we
are importing reveal.js which is the
engine for the presentation and
highlight JS to highlight and animate
our code then we are initializing
reveal.js with the Highlight plugin we
also have to add a reveal class to our
body and inside of it we create a div
with a slides class here is where we
will put our slides and we're good to go
creating slide is super easy all we have
to do is go inside of the div with this
lights glass and add a couple of
sections with some text inside of it
just by doing that our page will now
look like this each section has become a
slide we get a nice animation a progress
bar we can navigate with the keyboard
and we even get a navigation indicator
if we add sections inside of a section
we get vertical slides as shown by the
navigation indicator if we add the data
background color attribute to a section
that will change the background of the
slide and we will even get a super nice
color transition to display code inside
of a section we use the pre and code tax
that will give us a slide with a block
of code that looks like this to give
numbers to the lines of code we can add
the data line and numbers attribute
which will result in our code looking
like this the data line numbers
attribute is pretty powerful we can use
it to selectively highlight parts of the
code like on this case where we are
saying that we want to highlight lines 1
to 4 line 7 and line 11. this will give
us a result like this if we want to we
can also highlight our code step by step
like here where we are saying we want to
First highlight the lines one to four
then lines six to eight and then lines
10 and 11. so when we go to that slide
as we navigate with the keyboard each
part of the code will be highlighted on
the order we wrote fragments are another
cool feature that allow us to reveal
elements on a slide one by one with an
animation adding this slide that
contains a bunch of P tags with a
fragment class will have this effect
each P tag will be rebuilt one by one as
the user presses the right arrow on the
keyboard if we want to just by adding a
class name we can specify the animation
used when the fragments are revealed if
we wrap our fragments with a div that
has a r stack class the fragments will
show one by one on top of each other
animating elements between slides is
super easy here we have two slides with
a data auto animate attribute because
both of these slides have an H1 that
says hello review.js will detect them as
equal elements and it will animate their
position between the two slides this
also works with lists here we have two
slides with two lists as you can see c c
plus and Rost are on both lists and both
slides have the data auto animate
attribute so now when we go to the
slides our list will be beautifully
animated we can even animate a custom
HTML elements like here where we have a
400 by 400 box with a border radius of
10 pixels on the first slide and on the
second slide we have the same box but
with a border radius of 200 pixels since
this is just a div reveal.js can't
possibly know that the div from the
first slide is the same as the second
one this is why we write the data ID on
both boxes to tell reveal.js that they
are the same that will give us an
animation like so another cool thing
that reveal.js has is the overview mode
all we have to do is press the Escape
key and we will get a bird's eye view of
our slides reveal.js has a JavaScript
API that can control the presentation
programmatically it also has events if
you want to execute your own code when
something happens on the presentation
and it has all your plugins like a
markdown search notes math and zoom it
also has PDF export Touch navigation and
many other features that you should
explore as well I hope you found
reveal.js useful and I hope you start
making beautiful presentations with it
if you learned something new in this
video please press the like button share
it with your friends and subscribe to
the channel and don't forget that if you
want to learn things like JavaScript
python react react native gold Dart
flutter among many many others for
absolutely free all you have to do is
click the link below to join any of our
many free courses that you can take
right now absolutely free with me click
the link below and I will see you there
see you on the next one bye
thank you